# Shuangyue Yin (Moon)

Chatswood, NSW 2067 Mobile: 0420692221

Email: <a href="mailto:shuangyueyyy@gmail.com">shuangyueyyy@gmail.com</a>
Working Right: Australia citizen

#### **Career Brief**

I have three years web development experience working across different media agency companies. The projects I worked have gotten high satisfaction from the clients. My key technical skills are PHP for backend, CSS, JQuery as well as self-learning React for frontend, newsletter development and network hosting. I want to apply these skills into my career.

### **Technical Knowledge**

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript (JQuery, React), PHP

**Framework:** Bootstrap for CSS, React for Javascript

Computer Systems: Windows, Mac OS, Linux

#### **Education**

#### **Master of Information Technology Professional**

Feb 2012 - Feb 2014

Monash Universiy, Melbourne, Australia

Key skills: Internet Application Development, Enterprise Application Development for the Web, Network Security, Distributed Database

#### **Bachelor of Computer Science and Technology**

Sep 2007 - Jul 2011

Shan'xi University, Taiyuan, China

## **Professional Experience History**

Web Developer - Full-time Marketing Eye, Sydney, Australia Dec 2017 - Dec 2019

- PHP CMS development: Wordpress & Joomla
- Create Wordpress template from scratch based on Wordpress native API
- Revise Wordpress theme template
- Create new Wordpress functionality, such as different posts operations, build new functionality communicating with database and Wordpress API operation.
- Extend and customize Wordpress plugin functionality, such as WPBakery, RevolutionSlider, Contact Form 7 and ACF
- Create custom post type based on the client requirement and making it editable.
- Create Joomla module and create Joomla sites

- Maintain and upgrade website CMS
- Create and revise the front-end JQuery functionalities.
- Backend and frontend communication with Ajax
- Build CMS system with Laravel (MVC): create database mode, apply CRUD logic on controller, and build API for frontend consuming data and manipulate MySQL database
- Using Laravel Passport for authentication, restrict API access
- Using Axio and React to get data, store or destroy data from API endpoint and use React to control data on the frontend.
- Style page with CSS(SCSS)
- Website maintenance website backup and migration between staging site and live site; Hosting DNS maintenance.
- EDM create EDM based on design; create EDM template
- SEO check website SEO and present SEO report; fix technical SEO issue and improve the score of GTmatrics.
- React self-learning basic normal react development (set state and using state lifting communicate between parent and child component); React with Redux
- Guide and teach intern about newsletter and CMS

Key technic skills: PHP (Wordpress, Laravel), Database (MySQL), JavaScript (JQuery, React), CSS(Bootstrap 4 and Bootstrap 3), SEO, EDM, Apache hosting

#### Web Developer - Full-time Thinkun, Sydney, Australia

May 2017 - Dec 2017

- Develop Wordpress and PHP website or landing pages from scratch, install essential library from bower, create Gulp package if needed.
- Maintain websites and pages, update old or create new functionality.
- Build custom Wordpress theme template.
- Create and use custom post type and custom field of Wordpress to create editable fields of Wordpress dashboard.
- Style the page with CSS3.
- Create and revise the front-end JQuery and back-end PHP functionalities.
- Connect 3rd party Restful API and create functionality to communicate with the API.
- Create EDM system (Sendgrid, Mailchimp) template and connect API to implement confirmation, notification and other functionalities.

Key technic skills: PHP (Wordpress), Database (MySQL), JavaScript (JQuery), CSS

#### Web Developer - Contract The day of design, Sydney, Australia

Jan 2017 - Mar 2017

- Developing front-end part for PIA C-portal system. The tasks including creating whole PIA c-portal dashboard system pages using HTML5 code based on Bootstrap framework, using CSS(SCSS) to create basic style of the site, setting Google Map (basic Map configuration, Map info content) of the site and creating functional part via Jquery.
- Building a website (neuroscienceforleaders.com) by Wordpress based on the Wordpress Template. Using template widgets to create pages.

Key technic skills: PHP (Wordpress), JavaScript (JQuery), CSS

#### Web Developer - Internship I-Motor, Sydney, Australia

#### Oct 2016 - Jan 2017

- Building new websites based on the website template: create site basic configuration files; create database tables of the site; create new or migrate old data to the site tables; find old sites exceptions if migrate old site data to new sites so as to create new different sites based on template; development new website including front-end JQuery and CSS development and back end ASP development; test website between different browser and device when the finishing the site development.
- Updating website content by changing ASP file, including revising and adding HTML markup structure, changing SQL query statement.
- Updating website style by adding and changing CSS and Javascript code.
- Creating or updating database table and data when website needing to update.
- Contact website clients when their request finishing.
- Using photoshop resizing images according to client's' need.

#### IOS Developer- Internship Posmill, Sydney, Australia

Oct 2015 - Feb 2016

- Learned IOS development knowledge including the use of UI class, such as view, view controller, table view.
- Learned to use different frameworks such as Mantle, overcoat coping with data from JSON API to persist with core data, and familiar with the use of Cocoapods
- Helping to improve the basic functions including fix bugs, increase software speed and optimize the UI of software and create new functions
- Integrating JSON type data from Restful API between server and client via 3<sup>rd</sup> party class. Retrieving the customer data from client and returning the operated data back to service
- Using a variety of approaches including XIB, storyboard and code to realize UI design and based on different type of IOS device setting their performance
- Understanding logic level of code including the operation of different type of food product
- Being familiar with IOS develop centre and publish IOS app
- Adapting to, and learning new software and system quickly

# SEO & IT Support - Internship ACNW, Sydney, Australia

Feb 2015 - Apr 2015

- Helping clients to optimize their website, including improving the keyword rank of Google, helping them revise the content of their website so that search engine can get better ran result
- Providing keyword suggestion to client, including discuss with customer how to realize them
  expect keyword rank, showing the difficulty of their expected keyword via particular
  software and do a little revise so as to get better result
- Contacting with clients about their website optimize process via phone or email by showing the website rank change charts of last few weeks, and get their feedbacks
- Deal with difficult customers via particular ways

# References

Miroslav Hrubes 0422 704 569

Role: CTO of Marketing Eye

Abdullah Hadi 0434 961 435

Role: Teammate of Thinkun

Mark Hewitt-Park 0438 295 154

Role: Technical team manager of I-motor